export const mercuryQuestions = [
	{
		question: "What is the most notable feature of Mercury's orbit?",
		options: [
			'A) It has the most circular orbit in the Solar System.',
			'B) It is the only planet that orbits the Sun in less than an Earth year.',
			'C) It has the highest orbital speed of any planet.',
			'D) It is the only planet that rotates exactly three times for every two orbits around the Sun.',
		],
		correctOption: 'D',
	},
	{
		question: 'Why does Mercury have such extreme temperature variations?',
		options: [
			'A) It lacks an atmosphere to distribute heat.',
			'B) Its orbit takes it extremely close to and far from the Sun.',
			'C) It has no magnetic field.',
			'D) Its slow rotation period causes one side to heat excessively while the other freezes',
		],
		correctOption: 'D',
	},
	{
		question:
			"What is unique about Mercury's rotation period compared to its year?",
		options: [
			'A) One day is longer than one year.',
			'B) One day is exactly the same as one year.',
			'C) Mercury does not rotate.',
			"D) Mercury's rotation period is the shortest of all planets.",
		],
		correctOption: 'A',
	},
];

export const venusQuestions = [
	{
		question: "What is the most notable feature of Mercury's orbit?",
		options: [
			'A) It has the most circular orbit in the Solar System.',
			'B) It is the only planet that orbits the Sun in less than an Earth year.',
			'C) It has the highest orbital speed of any planet.',
			'D) It is the only planet that rotates exactly three times for every two orbits around the Sun.',
		],
		correctOption: 'D',
	},
	{
		question: 'Why does Mercury have such extreme temperature variations?',
		options: [
			'A) It lacks an atmosphere to distribute heat.',
			'B) Its orbit takes it extremely close to and far from the Sun.',
			'C) It has no magnetic field.',
			'D) Its slow rotation period causes one side to heat excessively while the other freezes',
		],
		correctOption: 'D',
	},
	{
		question:
			"What is unique about Mercury's rotation period compared to its year?",
		options: [
			'A) One day is longer than one year.',
			'B) One day is exactly the same as one year.',
			'C) Mercury does not rotate.',
			"D) Mercury's rotation period is the shortest of all planets.",
		],
		correctOption: 'A',
	},
];

export const earthQuestions = [
	{
		question: "What makes Earth's atmosphere unique in the Solar System?",
		options: [
			'A) It contains free oxygen.',
			'B) It is the densest.',
			'C) It has the highest percentage of carbon dioxide.',
			'D) It is the only one with clouds.',
		],
		correctOption: 'A',
	},
	{
		question: 'Which of the following is NOT TRUE about Earth’s Moon?',
		options: [
			'A) It is the largest moon in the Solar System.',
			"B) It has a significant effect on Earth's tides",
			'C) It is the fifth largest moon in the Solar System.',
			'D) It has a synchronous rotation with Earth.',
		],
		correctOption: 'B',
	},
	{
		question: "What is Earth's primary source of heat energy?",
		options: [
			'A) Volcanic activity.',
			'B) The Sun',
			'C) Radioactive decay in the core.',
			'D) Chemical reactions in the atmosphere.',
		],
		correctOption: 'B',
	},
];

export const marsQuestions = [
	{
		question:
			'What geological feature on Mars is the largest volcano in the Solar System?',
		options: [
			'A) Olympus Mons.',
			'B) Mariner Valley.',
			'C) Hellas Basin.',
			'D) Tharsis Bulge.',
		],
		correctOption: 'optionA',
	},
	{
		question:
			'Mars is home to the largest canyon in the Solar System, what is its name?',
		options: [
			'A) Grand Canyon.',
			'B) Valles Marineris.',
			'C) Olympus Chasma.',
			'D) Tharsis Rift.',
		],
		correctOption: 'optionB',
	},
	{
		question: "What is the main reason for Mars' red color?",
		options: [
			'A) Its atmosphere scatters blue light.',
			'B) The presence of water.',
			'C) The high iron oxide (rust) content in its soil.',
			'D) Reflections from its two moons.',
		],
		correctOption: 'optionC',
	},
];

export const jupiterQuestions = [
	{
		question:
			'Jupiter is known for a giant storm called the Great Red Spot. What is it?',
		options: [
			'A) A volcanic eruption.',
			'B) A hurricane-like storm.',
			'C) A large mountain.',
			'D) A red desert.',
		],
		correctOption: 'optionB',
	},
	{
		question: 'How many moons does Jupiter have?',
		options: ['A) 4', 'B) 67', 'C) Over 79', 'D) 12'],
		correctOption: 'optionC',
	},
	{
		question: "What is unique about Jupiter's moon Io?",
		options: [
			'A) It is covered in ice.',
			'B) It has the most volcanic activity in the Solar System.',
			'C) It is the largest moon of Jupiter.',
			'D) It has a subsurface ocean.',
		],
		correctOption: 'optionB',
	},
];

export const saturnQuestions = [
	{
		question: 'What is most distinctive about Saturn?',
		options: [
			'A) Its rings.',
			'B) It is the largest planet in the Solar System.',
			'C) It has the most moons.',
			'D) It has a solid surface.',
		],
		correctOption: 'optionA',
	},
	{
		question:
			"Which of Saturn's moons is known to have geysers erupting from its surface?",
		options: ['A) Titan.', 'B) Enceladus.', 'C) Rhea.', 'D) Iapetus.'],
		correctOption: 'optionB',
	},
	{
		question:
			'Saturn is the only planet in the Solar System that is less dense than water.',
		options: [
			'A) True.',
			'B) False.',
			'C) Only true for its core.',
			'D) True for all gas giants.',
		],
		correctOption: 'optionA',
	},
];

export const uranusQuestions = [
	{
		question: 'Uranus is unique because it:',
		options: [
			'A) Has rings like Saturn.',
			'B) Is tilted on its side, with an axial tilt of about 98 degrees.',
			'C) Has the most moons.',
			'D) Is the smallest gas giant.',
		],
		correctOption: 'optionB',
	},
	{
		question: 'What is the main component of Uranus’s atmosphere?',
		options: [
			'A) Hydrogen and helium.',
			'B) Methane.',
			'C) Ammonia.',
			'D) Water vapor.',
		],
		correctOption: 'optionB',
	},
	{
		question: 'Which of the following moons orbits Uranus?',
		options: ['A) Europa.', 'B) Titan.', 'C) Miranda.', 'D) Callisto.'],
		correctOption: 'optionC',
	},
];

export const neptuneQuestions = [
	{
		question: 'What is Neptune most known for?',
		options: [
			'A) Its blue color, due to methane in the atmosphere.',
			'B) Being the hottest planet.',
			'C) Having the most ringss.',
			'D) Its solid surface.',
		],
		correctOption: 'optionA',
	},
	{
		question: "Neptune's moon Triton is unique because it:",
		options: [
			'A) Is the largest in the Solar System.',
			'B) Orbits in the opposite direction of Neptune’s rotation, known as a retrograde orbit.',
			'C) Has active volcanoes like Io.',
			'D) Is covered entirely in water.',
		],
		correctOption: 'optionB',
	},
	{
		question: 'What phenomenon is observed in Neptunes atmosphere?',
		options: [
			'A) The Great Dark Spot, a storm similar to Jupiters Great Red Spot.',
			'B) Rings that are visible in the night sky.',
			'C) Frequent meteor showers.',
			'C) Frequent meteor showers.',
		],
		correctOption: 'optionA',
	},
];

export const questionsMap = {
	Mercury: mercuryQuestions,
	Venus: venusQuestions,
	Earth: earthQuestions,
	Mars: marsQuestions,
	Jupiter: jupiterQuestions,
	Saturn: saturnQuestions,
	Uranus: uranusQuestions,
	Neptune: neptuneQuestions,
};
